<controlOverlay>
  <family>PHYSICAL AND ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION</family>
  <rationale flag="true">ICS may support critical activities which will be needed for safety and reliability even in the absence of reliable power from the public grid</rationale>
  <control number="PE-11">
    <title>EMERGENCY POWER</title>
    <default value="2"/>
    <impact value="1"/>
    <guidance flag="true">Emergency power production, transmission and distribution systems are a type of ICS that are required to meet extremely high performance specifications. The systems are governed by international, national, state and local building codes, must be tested on a continual basis, and must be repaired and placed back into operations within a short period of time. Traditionally, emergency power has been provided by generators for short to mid-term power (typically for fire and life safety systems, some IT load, and evacuation transport) and UPS battery packs in distribution closets and within work areas to allow some level of business continuity and for the orderly shutdown of non-essential IT and facility systems. Traditional emergency power systems typically are off-line until a loss of power occurs and are typically on a separate network and control system specific to the facility they support. New methods of energy generation and storage (e.g., solar voltaic, geothermal, flywheel, microgrid, distributed energy) that have a real-time demand and storage connection to local utilities or cross connected to multiple facilities should be carefully analyzed to ensure that the power can meet the load and signal quality without disruption of mission essential functions.</guidance>
  </control>
  <enhancement number="1">
    <title>LONG-TERM ALTERNATE POWER SUPPLY - MINIMAL OPERATIONAL CAPABILITY</title>
    <default value="3"/>
    <impact value="1"/>
    <guidance flag="false"/>
  </enhancement>
  <enhancement number="2">
    <title>LONG-TERM ALTERNATE POWER SUPPLY - SELF-CONTAINED</title>
    <default value="4"/>
    <impact value="3"/>
    <guidance flag="false"/>
  </enhancement>
</controlOverlay>
